There we go. Recording has started. Uh,
if you want to admit everybody now,
Jorge, please go right on ahead.
>> All right, here we go.
>> Alrighty. Good morning, everyone. Um, as
we're still waiting for a few people to
join, um, my name is Ian Dunn. I am the
chair of the dosage administration and
clinical practice committee. Um, welcome
everyone. I hope you had a good holiday
season and are ready to start this new
year fresh. Uh, if you wanted to bring
up the slideshow, Dominic.
>> Yeah. Uh, I am going to bring up the one
with the agenda first. Give me just a
moment.
>> Okay.
>> And it's should be working on it now.
There we go.
And there there is the agenda. and then
I'll switch over to your slides after
this one again.
>> Okay. Yeah. So, uh here's our agenda for
the day. It's just brief member
introductions. Get to know all of you
guys that are going to be helping us
out. Your area of expertise, just what
you have to provide, even if it's not um
say a professional level of expertise.
Any expertise is appreciated especially
from our community. um as well as we
want to know why you're interested
interested
um about dosage administration and
clinical practice. So today we're going
to go ahead and um review our committee
authority and purpose. We'll review and
adopt our bylaws and we'll look over our
scope and work plan discussion.
>> [clears throat]
>> All righty, everyone. So, welcome. This
is the dosage administration clinical
practice committee. Um, thank you guys
for attending today's meeting. This
meeting serves as an orientation to the
dosage administration clinical practice
committee. It's an initial meeting for
our committee members. Uh and we do just
want to inform you guys if you decide to
participate today, it does not obligate
service long term. It's just to help us
develop this program. Um and you are
willing if as much as you are willing to
volunteer, we are willing to accept.
All right, next slide.
So the purpose of today's meeting is
three-fold. We wanted to um explain the
committee's purpose, authority, and
scope of work so everyone has a clear
understanding of how this committee fits
within the medical psilocybin program.
Second, we will review and consider
adoption of the committee bylaws um
which establish how this committee
operates.
Um third, we will provide space for
questions and initial participation in
committee decisions. This meeting is
meant to be informative, transparent,
and interactive. Um so we really just
want to hear from you guys. Uh, next
slide.
All right. And for any of you guys who
have been in our committees, this is
going to be a refresher, but for anyone
that's new, uh, committees operate in an
advisory comma capacity. They do not
replace the board and they do not act
independently of the board. Um, one of
the primary reasons committees exist is
to allow people with relevant expertise
to contribute meaningfully to program
development. So even when they may h not
be able to serve on the board itself due
to a real or perceived conflict of
interest, we'll allow them to
participate in the committees. That way
we can still get their expert input but
without um you know risking those
conflict of interest things because we
have a conflict of interest free board
and committees support the board by
expanding community input. They
incorporate subject matter expertise and
they increase participation in the
development of safe, effective and
evidenceinformed policy.
Next slide.
All right. So, this committee serves
strictly in an advisory role to the
medical psilocybin advisory board. While
this meeting functions as an initial
meeting for the committee, it is
important to be very clear about
authority and limitations. This
committee may recommend policy and
clinical guidance including dosage
ranges, administration protocols, and
practice considerations. However, it
does not make the final regulatory
decisions. Final authority rests with
the medical psilocybin advisory board
for recommendations and ultimately with
the department secretary for
promulgating rules and regulations. Our
role is to inform those decisions with
sound clinical reasoning, scientific
evidence, and careful consideration of
safety.
Next slide.
Another reminder, committee service is
voluntary, advisory, and non-exclusive.
Members may serve on more than one
committee, and participation is intended
to be flexible while still meaningful.
The goal is to bring together diverse
expertise without creating unnecessary
barriers to participation.
And that's kind of the committee
structure. So now let's look at the
specifics for the dosage administration
and clinical practice committee. Uh
so the responsibilities of this
committee are substantial and important
of course. Um this committee will
recommend dosage ranges and
administration protocols for medical
psilocybin use grounded in current
scientific literature. We will also
recommend guidance on therapeutic
structures including preparation,
session duration, environmental
conditions and in integration
expectations. A key responsibility is
analyzing the clinical research and
available data to define clear dosage
parameters um both minimum effective
doses and maximum safety limits across
different you know therapeutic or
consumer contexts.
Next slide.
So, now that we've gotten the, you know,
um, explaining out of the way, if you
wish to serve or participate in this
committee, please, um, raise your hand
using the teams function. He'll be
bringing up a slide to explain how to do
that. We're going to ask that you share
your name, your role, or any area of
expertise, and your perspective or
interest related to dosage
administration and clinical practice.
Good morning everybody. If you are
interested in speaking and serving on
the committee and introducing yourself,
please go ahead and raise your hand. If
you are on a computer, the hand icon is
near the top of the team's window and it
says raise under the icon. If you are on
the team's app on a phone, please press
the ellipses or the three dots in the
menu and then the hand icon will appear
and you can select it. If you are
joining through voice only on a phone,
press star five to raise or lower your
hand.
Dr. Trish, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Good morning. Hi, I'm Trish Singh and
I'm a um LPCC in Albuquerque, New
Mexico. I'm the owner of a new awakening
counseling agency serving um
courtappointed or courtmandated
persons um in Bernalo County um as a
mental health and substance abuse
clinic. My primary um practice is in
mental health and substance abuse. I
have been studying and apprenticing in
the psychedelic realm and am also
licensed in Colorado currently and
hoping to bring um psychedelic assisted
therapy to um my the population I work
with here in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
So, I'm super honored and privileged to
be here today and appreciate your time.
>> Thank you very much,
>> Mary. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hello. Uh my name is Barry Dunan. I'm
one of the co-founders and president for
Rio Grand Analytics. Uh we're one of the
cannabis testing labs here in New
Mexico. Uh but we've genu generated some
preliminary data uh quantifying six
different phosphorolated tryptoines. Uh
so we could help with dosage and making
recommendations there. uh of those
tryptoamines, psilocin, norsilicin, and
psil uh psilocybin are included. Uh so I
just wanted to let you know we're an
analytical lab here that can offer
support.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Dr. Leah, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you so much for having me. I'm Dr.
Lita Feti. I'm um an internal medicine
physician. worked at University of New
Mexico for a decade as an academic
hospitalist. So, you know, I saw the um
really the worst pathology you can see
in the entire state uh and taught uh for
a decade uh there which with pleasure
and learned so much through our
wonderful patients and the underserved
community of New Mexico and the
surrounding states. And now uh we have
uh we have uh a hospice program. So, I'm
an end of life um physician. Um and we
also have our uh conscious physicians
psychedelics academy where we uh train
facilitators
um at different actually doses uh uh for
um facilitation of psilocybin and
everything has been evidence-based and
um it's going really well. It started in
January. It's a nine-month program. Um
but I have deep experience with this
medicine for over a decade um both
personally and also in facilitation in
other countries. Um so it's a pleasure
to be here and it's truly a privilege to
be part of this uh this moment in in New
Mexico history and for our country and
and really globally. Thank you for
having me.
>> Thank you very much.
Shane, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> All right. Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> All right. Um, first off, I'm having
that same problem with uh chat um where
it won't let me enter anything in the
chat, but um my name is Shane McDaniel.
Um currently I'm a uh integration coach.
Um and I'm also going to be hopefully um
entering into the cultivation world.
Um my experience with it is is pretty
vast. I've u experienced quite a bit
with psychedelic assisted therapy from a
healing point of view. Um also like I
said as a coach um I've assisted other
people in their journeys.
That's it.
>> Thank you very much.
>> James, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Morning everyone. Ian Dominic. My name
is James Brown and I am a doctor of
pharmacy here in New Mexico um out of
UNM and um I'm very excited to be part
of this committee. Um you know my
expertise is um I've been trained as a
psilocybin facilitator in Oregon and
done my training in and everything
there. Um, I wanted to let everybody
know that very recently I've been in
agreement with Emerald Valley Institute,
which is a training facility to bring
them to New Mexico. So, we will be
bringing that institution and training
program to New Mexico to offer that at a
very cost-effective price. And I'm very
excited to have that because we are
the program has so much to offer New
Mexico as a as a reference. And so we'll
be here for you guys if um you need any
of that as well as other New Mexicans.
Um but more to come on that, but that's
just new exciting information. Um and
I'm just very excited to be part of this
committee because of what it does with
our clinical research with this. I
really want to focus on the preparation
as well as integration piece as well. Um
all of this falls together. Um thank you
everyone.
>> Thank you.
Ellen, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Good morning everyone. My name is Joelyn
Shimls, but I go by Ellen. I'm excited
to be here. I'm a nurse practitioner in
Albuquerque and have been working in
mental health for almost 30 years. I'm
trained in sever several therapeutic
modalities and female health patient. I
work primarily with PTSD, depression,
anxiety, substance use disorder, OCD,
and I work specifically with nurses and
other health care workers, first
responders, and veterans. I'm also a
veteran myself. I served 23 years active
duty in the Army. Um, I with deployments
myself to Iraq and Afghanistan,
[clears throat] and I'm a clinical
professor at Emory University. So, I
work with the Emory Center for
Psychedelics and Spirituality, and I
teach in the psychiatric mental health
nurse practitioner program there. and I
own a mental health private practice
here in Albuquerque and I've been
trained through the Integrative
Psychiatry Institute. Um, as a
clinician, educator, and researcher, I'm
very pleased to join this committee and
and thank you everyone for all the work
that you've done so far. I'm so
impressed with everything that's been
happening in all the meetings. Um, I'm
particularly interested in how dosing
and administration practices will
interact with clinical context um, and
with patient vulnerability and
facilitator training. Um, as I've heard
some other people talk about, I'm
looking forward to talking about how
standards can be designed. Um, really
evolving with this evidence base. So, I
look forward to collaborating with this
amazing interdisciplinary group um, to
help shape these recommendations for the
state. Thank you.
>> Thank you,
>> Cameron. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself and speak.
Hi everyone. Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, great. Uh, yeah, my name is
Cameron Burgard. My degree is in
biochemistry. I currently work as a
laboratory scientist. Um I have many
years of research experience uh
delivering nanoparticle drug delivery
for cancer and I also have about one and
a half decades of u dosing various
psychedelics for um all kinds of people.
So um yeah I've read just about every
research paper there is to read. So, I
think my technical understanding of
psychedelics is really good. Uh, and I'd
like to lend that to everyone.
>> Thank you.
>> Aaliyah, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
Okay. Hello. Can you hear me?
>> Yes, we can.
>> Okay. Had to take me a moment to find
the unmute. Um, my name is Aaliyah
Dodie. I'm a doctor of oriental medicine
in Santa Fe, New Mexico. And
[clears throat]
um
I've been studying a lot about medical
use of psychedelics especially
psilocybin
and am interested in
potentially working with people in that
arena especially with uh micro doing um
and also working in collaboration with
uh other healthc care providers and
counselors psycho psychotherapists
um for do working with um fuller doses
and um
uh I do a lot with um supporting people
with nervous system regulation and I'm
very interested in trauma healing work
and
so as a um doctor of oriental medicine
we are in New Mexico we're considered
primary healthc care practitioners
primary health care doctors and Um and
then the craniocyacchrother therapy I I
practice biodnamic craniosacy therapy
which is also really amazing work for
helping people to um very gently unwind
what's held in the nervous system and
body and energy body. So just interested
in seeing and supporting this and moving
forward in a in a great way um to serve
the broadest
number of people in New Mexico and in a
safe supported way and and an affordable
way.
Not sure what else to say.
Thank you very much,
Julie. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
Julie, your mic has been enabled. Please
Okay.
To the next person.
Brett, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hey, good morning everybody. Can you
hear me? Okay.
>> Yes, we can.
>> Okay, great. Um, thank you guys. Uh, my
name is Brett Phelps and I am an
attorney based in Las Vegas, New Mexico.
Um, I live in Moa, New Mexico. uh have a
lot of um practice and experience with
uh drug policy in general. Very
interested in in the nitty-gritty of the
of the regulations. um fairly familiar
with the the psychedelic realm, not at
the the scientific or practitioner level
as as some of y'all, but yeah, really
love getting into the nitty-gritty of
the the regulations and rules and how to
fine-tune that to make it as as
functional as possible, as accessible as
possible, and as affordable as possible
for as many of New Mexicans as we can.
So, happy to be here. Yeah, nice to meet
all you guys and see y'all again that uh
yeah, we've been working with a little
bit. Thanks.
Thank you,
Katherine. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Good morning, everyone. My name is
Katherine Waro. I am located in Los
Cusus, New Mexico. Um, I am a licensed
counselor and I have a private practice,
Mariposa Counseling Center. I am I am
trauma informed and I've been doing this
work for about four years now. Um I have
seen extreme success with uh psilocybin
in particular. Um I'm very very grateful
to be here. I've been attending as many
of these subcommittees as possible. Um
I'd like to contribute in any way that
um I can. I'm very grateful to everybody
here dedicating their time and effort.
Um, my focus is primarily on health
equity, safety, and I really want to try
to keep things in New Mexico. I'm really
concerned about out ofstate interests
coming in and uh the money leaving the
state. Um, but I'm here and I'll be
participating as much as uh you allow me
to. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you,
Chris. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
Hello everyone. Can you hear me?
>> Yes, we can.
>> Excellent. Hi, my name is Chris
Viskuski. I'm a advisory board member
and I'm the chair of the propagation
committee and I'll probably be involved
pretty heavily with this committee as
well in one capacity or another and I
just wanted to um say good morning to
everybody and I hope you have a good
day. I can't stay long this morning um
but I'll be around. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Your mic has been enabled. Please unmute
yourself to speak.
>> Good morning. I'm happy to be here. My
name is Gregory Evans. I am here. I am
not a doctor. Um leed and humbled to be
in this room. Uh thank you everyone for
being here. Um I will be attending a lot
of committees. I have a lot of interests
but related to dosage and
administration. [clears throat] I'm very
focused on
um [clears throat] monitoring how we
define dosage, how we provide the
analytics and how that gets uh
distributed on an education platform to
the facilitators. um [clears throat]
specifically would love to um get some
time with you Barry uh to talk about um
[clears throat]
you know what what what your what your
company is looking to do uh for uh the
analytics part of the compliance
pipeline. Um, I have a framework of
dosage that I've been working on that
basically levels everything out to a
single a unified solution equivalency
so that all disperate cultivars that
have different potencies and different
profiles and different alkaloids
contained in them can be like dosed on
an even platform. And then we can then
look at the unique qualifying profiles
that differentiate one cultivar to the
next.
Um I think that it's an important aspect
in harm reduction to make sure that we
know what's going in a dose because
there are so many variable variables on
the recipient's side that we don't
really have the pot the ability to
measure. Um, and I want to make sure
that we get as much science behind
what's going in so that the
psychologists and psychiatrists and
therapists can provide the research,
what's coming out, what the efficacy is
of those things. I also want to stand up
a conversation around what micro doing
is, how it's applied, and hopefully
provide a structure for framework where
we can allow certain types of tiered
dosages to be
uh executed in a non-clinical setting.
Eg take two of these and call me in the
morning. um micro doing protocol should
be done on a regular cadence fourish
days a week and people can't really go
into a facility on that cadence. That is
all.
Thank you,
>> James. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
Hello and good morning everybody. My
name is James Hassov and I'm from
Arizona. I am affiliated with the
Arizona Department of Health Services
where I'm a biomed research analyst.
It's a pleasure to be with you all here
today and I think my biggest area of
interest is how to go about the pre and
post session integration and
preparation. I do deeply believe that
medical psilocybin has the ability to
help therapeutically. However, I also
think that there needs to be a really
big importance for pre and post um
psychotherapy.
So, thank you very much for having me
and I'm very interested in learning from
everybody.
>> Thank you.
And that is everyone who has raised
their hands. There's a few comments in
the chat that I I will uh read. Uh
Gregory Evans was just testing. Uh Eric
Baka has a uh extensive um text here
message here about the formula to
measure total consumable. I won't read
that. Uh that might take a bit of time,
but folks if uh if you can't read that
uh we can we can make that available to
you. Uh this video will be uploaded.
Uh Shane McDaniel says, "I did a restart
and chat is working for now." And
Deborah Thorne says, "Hello everyone.
I'm obained patients right now. My de is
my name is Dr. Deb Thorne, doctor of
medical science, physician associate and
certive integrative psychiatry and
psychedelic practitioner. I am
representing the southern part of the
state as a nonprofit and medical
provider. I've been trained and have
worked with psilocybin therapy for the
past 5 years legally out of state and in
Canada. Glad to be here and listening in
on everyone's input towards regulations.
I hope to add my acquired knowledge and
experience towards this meaningful
program. And we have one more hand up.
Larry, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself.
>> Unmute.
>> Buenos. Good morning.
All right. Sounds like you guys can hear
me.
>> My name is Larry de la Cruz. I am a US
Navy veteran. I am also a dispensary
owner that focuses completely
on removing stigmatization of these that
a lot of people will call drugs but and
it's not it's simply an alternative
medicine that can be used. So my focus
with my businesses has always been
education first. Education is always a
must in order to treat people and start
lowest dose possible. So titration was
always the word that I always use with
individuals. Uh I have been a cultivator
for the last 5 years myself. Um and
being a US Navy veteran with PTSD, it
has helped me tremendously. So to be any
part any part of this is immensely just
puts a great smile on my face. So, thank
you for everything that you all are
doing and this committee is doing
because
these are medicines that could help
individuals better than I believe better
than pharmaceuticals honestly or in
combination. Um, yeah, thank you so much
for your time.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, that looks like that's everyone.
>> Well, perfect. Um so what we can go
ahead and do now is go toward the bylaws
and then we can open up um
[clears throat] our initial you know
work plan discussion what we want to
move on first but if you could open the
bylaws for me I have some trouble
sharing my screen. Thank you.
All right [clears throat] if it will
open on my side that would be great.
Cool. All right. So um the name of this
committee obviously the dosage
administration clinical practice
committee it's established and operates
under the medical psilocybin advisory
board. The purpose of this committee is
to develop evidence-based safety focused
recommendations related to psilocybin
dosing administration procedures and
clinical
research and emerging best practices. So
we also look at therapeutic structure
guidance. We're going to recommend um
guidance on that therapeutic structure
including but not limited to their
preparation requirements, how long a
session is, um the environmental
conditions and post administration and
integration expectations.
Another thing we're going to have to do
as a committee is analyze peer-reviewed
clinical research, observational data,
and real world evidence to define clear
dosage parameters. Um we also are going
to need to do risk and safety
assessments. look at each patient, see
what our contraindications are, what are
our adverse side effects, what is a
disqualifying condition, things like
that. Um, ongoing review and updates.
So, we need to establish and maintain a
process for periodic review of emerging
scientific literature. That just means
if um we make a dosage recommendation
and then a brand new study comes out
that contradicts us, well, we have to
review that evidence, see if it was all
it was stacked up to be, and then apply
it to the program.
So the committee membership is um
individuals with expertise in clinical
practice, psychiatry, psychology,
pharmarmacology, nursing, public health
or related disciplines as well as public
members where appropriate and members
shall serve serve at the pleasure of the
board. Um the committee chair shall be
appointed by the chair of the board.
Um
the chair is responsible for presiding
over meetings, setting meeting agendas,
ensuring timely development and serving
as the primary liaison.
Um then the meetings may be conducted
virtually in person or in hybrid format.
Usually I prefer teams just for the fact
that we are the fifth largest
geographical state in the union. Um so
trying to get people from all over to
come to one physical location seems
overly burdensome. So, I just prefer to
have it on teams where anyone from all
over the state can help out. I don't
want to limit it to just Albuquerque uh
having an input. I want all of the
state. Um and then voting and
recommendations. All of our things are
basically a majority vote. Um
all of our resolutions will be
transmitted in writing to the board once
passed. They are advisory in nature and
um we do want that the committee members
disclose any potential conflicts of
interest. We're not saying that you are
disqualified immediately, but we should
be able to
look at what your biases are and then
analyze the decision as well just to
make sure that everything is above
board. Not trying to disqualify anyone.
I'm just trying to make sure that when
we make this program, we're making it
for the people of New Mexico.
And um these bylaws can be amended upon
recommendation of the committee or at
the board's discretion. So, pretty basic
standard stuff. Um I'll open discussion
on it. If anyone has any questions,
comments, concerns about the bylaws or
would like to make amendments, please
raise your hand now.
Seeing no discussion, we will go ahead
and uh move to a vote on the bylaws. So
uh what I want you guys to go ahead and
do is if you are in favor of um if you
had introduced yourself and are welcome
to being a part of the ma the committee
if you are in favor of adopting the
bylaws please use the team's raise your
hand function. Now,
>> and Ian, there are 15 people with their
hands raised. Uh if those individuals
could lower your hands at this time.
>> Okay. And everyone's hands are lowered
at this point. Ian.
>> All right. So, anyone opposed, please
raise your hands.
With 15 yeses and zero nos, the motion
is passed and the bylaws are adopted.
Um, and now we can go ahead and move on
to work plan discussion. So, I want to
hear from you guys. Um, what is your
priority? What do you want to focus on
first? Um, and that kind of thing. I
I'll go ahead and um lead over to our
committee members.
Ian, since we don't we don't have any
hands raised, uh, I can go ahead and
read some things in the chat then.
>> Oh, yeah, actually. All right.
>> Oh, we got a hand. Go for
>> Yeah, we do have a hand. All right, here
we go.
James, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you again. Um, some of some of the
stuff I'd like to see us focus on as a
committee, like you had alluded to, Ian,
was there's a lot of research out there
already that's that's set for dosings
and times, right? So, administration
session times are going to be important.
Um, as well as the dose that is
administered at that time. Um, some of
the stuff too I'd like to see is um,
who's going to be administering the
dose? Um, that's a big question that's
out there. Can the patient do it? can
somebody else do it? Um, in the medical
model, you know, we're used to handing
people stuff and administering stuff
where in this model, a lot of itself um
the the person self- administers and
self does a lot. So, just something to
think about, but I'd like to really see
us talk about um you know, the dosing,
the maximums, but really session times
with dose will be important. Um, and I'd
really like to see us discuss that. And
I think that Oregon is a little
different than Colorado. So, we want to
just see what what's out there in
contrast um to see what the New Mexico
model specifically will be. Um that's I
think an important thing that people
keep talking about is this is New
Mexico, so we need to make sure this is
New Mexico specific with the guidelines
that are out there. But can we tailor it
to a little bit more of New Mexico
style? Um I think we can. So, um just a
thought, an idea. Um, and again, uh, my
disclosures would be that I have, uh, a
nonprofit that is a veteranled because I
am a veteran, um, that's disabled and I
served eight years in the Navy, um, and
continue to help vets. Um, and I think
this is a great thing. Um, but that's my
disclosures is that I, um, have a
nonprofit that's veteran and first
responderbased force psychedelics as
well as, um, this school. I'm going to
be bringing Emerald Valley Institute to
New Mexico. Um, it'll be a New Mexico
based program and so I'm really excited
to offer that to New Mexicans. But those
are my two disclosures just to make sure
I'm upfront. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you,
Dr. Lita. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you so much. I have to second what
James was saying about dosing and
administration and you know because it's
wildly different. This medicine is
wildly different in it effects um and
whether people are able to take it
themselves versus having a guide. So
based on dosage, if we're talking about
micro doing there are many experts here
on this um committee talking about you
know the details of that and um I
totally agree that you know if you're
you know given a regimen for a person
who has treatment resistant depression
let's say in preparation to going into a
macro dose session then why shouldn't
they be able to have that agency to take
the medicine based on their needs and
also with the expertise of the guide um
with them in the preparatory phase and
then going into the macro dose with a
guide um in a safe setting and um
afterwards you know continuing on the
micro doing regimen that works for the
individual meeting them where they're
at. Um, so I think and and I think you
know one of the things that I see be
very effective for our New Mexico
population and yeah, our program was
developed on the on the land here, which
we're still uh grateful for, is uh
people here um tend to want more of that
agency. And it's very possible due to
the intergenerational trauma that we see
in the New Mexico population, people
don't um trust the the colonized method
of things where in even at UNM we would
see people not trust coming into the
hospital because we you know as
physicians as NPAs, nurses, the medical
industrial complex we force people to
take a particular dose of something and
you have to do it in a particular
regimen. Um, you know, we train people,
our facilitators are trained to meet
people where they're at. This person may
need a micro dose once a week. They may
need a micro dose once a month. They may
need a micro dose for four days and then
off for three days. So, and then the
dosage matters, right? And so I think
all of those things need to be discussed
and uh considered in our population
because of uh their special um their
special wants and they should they
should have agency in saying hey I think
50 milligrams is good for me or
somebody's saying hey I think at 200
milligrams I you know I feel the effects
of the medicine and I'm no longer
suicidal and then you know the macro
dose journey is a whole different thing.
But it's, you know, this medicine
teaches us decentralization and
connection with the sacred self and the
sacred fungi um and and the planet and
earth medicine. And so I think um it's
great to be, you know, talking about all
of that. You know, at what level of the
medicine, at what dosage do we need to
have to be in person with somehat
someone and at what dosage do we really
not?
>> Thank you.
>> And there are four more folks that I
will uh get to.
Shane, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Yeah, thank you. um kind of want to hit
a couple of different topics and and I
and Dominic I had already talked to you
about this so I I understand it with
regard to micro doing folks um it
doesn't look like that's going to be
able to happen because the way the bill
is written um you have to be in a
facility in a clinical setting to dose
any kind any dose um which pretty much
means and you and you have to and you
they will have to stay for a certain
amount of time right um which means
micro dosing is probably not going to
happen right away unless we can get
somehow the
um authors of the bill to change the
bill um to allow it. It's not going to
happen. Um regarding
dosing, it's um in Oregon and Colorado
complete two completely different
models. Oregon, as I said in the last
meeting, um based their
um flood dose or macro dose or heroic
dose on Terrence McKenna's minimum of
five grams. Um and we all have discussed
that um kind of at length. Um that
depends on you know the strain that
depends but that limiting it to 5 g I I
think is improper. Um for somebody who
um has experienced a lot of journeys 5 g
probably isn't going to be enough. For
somebody that may be a rookie and it's
their first time five grams probably is
too much. Um but that and it also you
know um depends on the person. um um you
know uh weight um and and that kind of
stuff. Um but I I I and then in Oregon I
mean and then in Colorado I think it's
up to the
provider um or the um person that is um
providing the medicine to determine what
the dose should be. Um I think that's a
probably a lot better model as long as
the people providing
are experts at what they're doing. um we
don't want to see people over to you
know getting too much. Um the other
thing I would like to um discuss is
um what the what this [snorts] committee
can
do regarding
required integration coaching.
um as somebody who is an integration
coach, I I I I I
came to that decision to be an
integration coach because I didn't
integrate properly on my first ex um
experience um with Iawaska and um I
realize the importance of integration
preparation and post um and I I think we
need to have some sort of
regulation regarding that that there
needs to be a minimum, you amount of
preparation integration and post
integration um so that we can make sure
that we are getting people
um the best outcome that they can get.
Right? If you just um say you can come
in and do the dose without integration
um studies have shown that it is very
ineffective or at least in comparison to
with integration. So I think we need to
look at
making sure that there is some minimum
level of integration.
Um and that's that's kind of where I
stand on these things. Thanks.
>> Thank you
>> Ellen. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you again. Um I would reiterate
what others have said um about
discussing dosing and the schedule
variables. So not just about the dose
but the format. Are we looking at single
session stepped repeated dosing? Um and
then preparatory dosing. What does that
all look like? I think timing and
environments are really going to be
crucial for this and the and looking at
what our parameters are for screening
for preparation and integration as
others have said. Um I think that we
have to be this is never going to be a
one-sizefits-all model. This has to be a
very patient centered approach. Um and
this has to be really part of a this is
one component of a larger therapeutic
system. So I think that whatever we do
allowing that there's going to be dosing
ranges um rather than fixed doses up
front is something that we need to
address. And if that's not possible, I
would say that would be one of the first
things we need to address. clear
criteria for what any kind of stepping
is going to look like. And then
obviously working with um the training
requirements and then um having it might
be that you know having specific
distinct protocols for different types
of dosing sessions and um of course
ongoing data collection as we move
forward with this. Thanks.
>> Thank you Ian. I'm just going to read a
few things in the chat right now. Um
see uh had an introduction by uh Ash
Shelton uh and uh let's see by Cameron
Burgard. I agree with Eric uh all the
information is correct. I would like to
add that by saying that from the
research my own experience I found that
there are many people's constitutions
and or mental defenses do not always
respond to suggested dosages.
>> [clears throat]
>> There are some people who are extremely
sensitive who responded dosages that
shouldn't have any effect probably due
to placebo effect. I've also overseen
beyond heroic dosages that have not
produced little to no effect. For
example, over 1k micrograms of LSD. Do
not believe in standardized dosage
perhaps as a theoretical starting point,
but I believe in practice starting from
zero and titrating up for each
individual is really important. It's
very easy to give someone a standard
dosage based on BMI and completely
overwhelmed people. Um let's see then uh
Zack Snder had a question about types of
treatments. Uh Deborah Thorne uh says as
per the organ program I think it's
important for the participant to handle
and prepare their medicines prior to
taking it. Zach uh will do address
individuals that are self-administering
under the care of a provider question.
Matthew. Uh, I am Matthew. I reside in
New Mexico. I'm here to participate as
observer. I do not own a business
relation. However, I'm an advocate and
have uh cultural experiences as a
native. Uh, Dominic added the uh bylaws
into the chat.
Uh, and then Zach, I think Zack Snder, I
think that dosing should apply to
providers providing medicine with
guideline for self-administration.
Deborah Thorne, let's also consider the
uniqueness of polymorphism in
individuals who may not respond to the
standard macro dose and thus make
accommodations for it. Uh Dr. Lita, is
the dosage not at all negotiable? That's
not safe. Could we change that through
the subcommittee?
Ash Shelton, absolutely. Pre and post
integration is crucial. And then Dominic
added to be clear one of the purposes of
this committee is to look at doses and
administration. So the suggestions and
comments being made and presented right
now are those people are offering and it
will be up to this committee to discuss
these issues and how administration will
occur for the board to make
recommendations.
And Marcus the bill says approved
settings uh are we not looking to avoid
the mistake made in Oregon?
Uh Katherine for macro dosing. I
practice updosing because each and each
person is unique in their response to
the medicine. From my experience over
the years, no one spec no one specific
dose works for everyone. Starting low
and up dosing to ego disillusion has
worked very well for me. I found that
most need two to 2.5 to four grams. Some
people find this isn't enough. I think
it's important to establish that by
offering only four grams first and a
subsequent treatment can be arranged for
higher doses are needed. Uh and then
I'll let's go back to folks who have
their hands raised and I'll get back to
the chat in just a bit.
Barry, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hey, thank you very much. Um my
questions uh circle around analytical
[snorts] capabilities and and support
from labs in New Mexico. Uh when and how
can we apply and what will be required
for the labs that will come in to
support uh the dosing for clinical
trials and things like that.
>> I just want to add something really
really quick. Um, so some people were
asking about the micro doing. So micro
doing is allowed. What's not allowed is
having them take that micro dose at
home. So what we could do is something
like um
how they do
um
h what's it called? There are certain
medications. I can't think of any that
are a little less harmful right now than
but like chemotherapy you go for um a
period to the hospital and then you
leave. So what I'm thinking is we may
not be able to do a micro dose at home,
but we may be able to do a micro dose
outpatient where you stop by, you get
your medication um and then are
discharged assuming you have a ride. Um
that's something we could we could look
into considering. And then um another
thing was someone said
this bill says approved settings are are
the bill says approved settings. Are we
not looking to avoid that mistake made
in Oregon? Well, we are. The mistake
made in Oregon was if you imagine like a
strip mall with a building where they're
all kind of attached. The Oregon law
said that only if there was a psilocybin
place in there, the entire thing that
entire strip mall would have had to be
psilocybin. What we did was we said,
"Okay, we have to approve settings, but
we're not going to say that this
building can only be for psilocybin."
And I think that's how we avoided that
mistake. Anyway, I'll yield back to the
comments.
>> Thank you, Ian.
Gregory, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Oh man, I have so much to say.
Um,
first
we need to adopt
unified language and definitions
around so many things. Um,
soap box number one, micro dosing. What
is a microdose?
Do we have a definition written into
law? [clears throat] Is it a good idea
to write that into law?
There's a lot of interpretation.
[clears throat]
Um I think we've all heard somebody,
yeah, I just took a little micro dose
today. I'm tripping just a little bit.
You know, and like if you're feeling the
effects of a micro dose, it is
1 th00 Well, it is 90% too strong,
right? So I think we really need to
understand what that definition is, how
it can be applied. If people are using
the term micro dose to say, you know,
tripping just a little bit like then
that's a different thing. That's like
mini dosing. We need to get into that.
We need standardized language and we
need to adhere to that language when
writing it into law.
Um
I will offer a scientific value of a
micro dose in solosin equivalency. A
solosin equivalency is going to be
take into account your psilocybin and
your solosin in the biomass and it is
going to calculate that into what your
body is has potential to absorb as
solosin. Um there's like historic do
like analytics that measure things in
psilocybin equivalency. That's one way
to look at it. And I'm going to push for
us to look at things in solosin
equivalency.
[clears throat]
Um
3 mg solosin to8 milligram solosin is a
micro dose.
BMI doesn't need to be taken into
account for this type of dosing.
Those levels of psilocybin are less
noticeable than any SRRI that we are
giving people in mass. This is a safe
dosage that should be able to go home
with people
in Oregon. There are things that there
are cafes or yoga centers where you can
go take a micro dose. You stay for an
hour do do a yoga class. This type of
solution is a barrier to access.
This does not create equity. This does
not help
Francine down on Country Road 75
who can't leave her house, doesn't like
to do yoga, but definitely needs this
medicine on a protocol basis and might
not want to shatter their ego.
There's so much in this medicine that
does not require full ego dissolution.
That is one thing that is valuable in a
specific context.
We cannot if we are looking at this from
perspective of equity, we cannot leave
the furthest reaches of the people who
need this the most out in the cold.
Moving on.
Um I'll read my comment so you can skip
it.
Um, we absolutely need to take the
concept of measuring biomass of full
body fruits out of the conversation.
When you say five grams of mushroom, you
are saying five g of variable and that
variable needs to be measured. We don't
know. I can give you a pile of five
grams and a pile of five grams and one
will make you trip so hard that you will
not know who you are for the next 12
hours. And then another one you could
probably drive a car, you know, and
because the biomass does not define
what's
being
converted in your body, what what you're
has no relevancy. Like we could go into
a gen bank sort of protocol where we
like make of that of 10,000
like
you know uh 10,000 cultures that we
freeze and and remove and fruit those
and highly defined conditions. So they
produce the exact same thing every
single day but with scinessence and
change and morphology.
um vary like phenotype variations inside
specific environments. We're going to
have so much variation in our biomass
that's produced and tested that we need
to calculate it based on
what is in what it can be converted in
the body and what the potential
actual dosage is from a solosin
equivalency perspective.
Uh I had one other thing contradictions.
I think that there needs to be room for
people to definitely needs to be room
for pe for like highly trained
knowledgeable facilitators, prescribers,
whoever is advising on medical um
consumption to be able to be like, "Hey,
cool. Yeah, I see that you've been on
like these SSRIs. you're coming off of
these you may need to like have a higher
dose here or a lower dose here. Um when
we get into complexities of many social
lower and micro non subperceptual
dosages that becomes a little bit
different than a conversation about
trying to achieve dis ego dissolution. I
do not like the term hero. Um I will I
will stand for not using that. Um, we
just basically we really really really
need to get get away from being like
five grams like five grams of what man
tell me five grams of what
and I will
uh
yield. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Ian, I'll read a few uh
messages in the chat. Uh by James Brown,
will a facilitator be able to administer
a session as an individual's residence?
Question. Uh it will be important to
have access at home. Uh Gregory also
added BMI is far less relevant than gut
health. This needs a detailed study.
Ellen says, "Yes, we have the
opportunity here to define the setting."
Deborah [clears throat] Thorne says,
"Additionally, let's not enforce
medication shaming and insist that those
on a psychotropic medications such as
Zolaf Paxel go through a wash out period
as this can cause [snorts] profound
destabilization.
This is why medical screening is
paramount."
Aaliyah says, "Is it true that micro
doing at home would not be legal under
New Mexico law? If so, this must be
changed." Gregory added, uh, what is our
definition of micro doing? Dr. Lita
says, in our patient population, that
doesn't really make sense. Uh, Ellen
says, like the methodone clinic model,
question mark, how inconvenient. Uh,
Gregory added uh to that comment. Uh,
please not. Cameron says, Aaliyah, that
is the goal of decriminalization in New
Mexico so that people can continue to
practice at home without the fear of uh
law enforcement officers. Uh, Greg
Evans, I totally agree that the word
that missing is titration. Jesse says,
not a micro dose if you feel it. Zach
added, a solution would be to have to be
way sorry, excuse me. A solution would
be to have to be way we give the
providers a process to administer
outside of facility have criter criteria
that the providers stipulate.
Uh, let's see. Okay, let's go. I'll put
a pause there and I'll put a pin there
and then we'll go to Eric for public
comment. Eric, your mic has been
enabled. Please unmute yourself to
speak.
>> Eric, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hello. Can you hear me?
>> Yes, we can.
Hello, my [clears throat] name's Eric
Baka. I wanted to just uh kind of follow
up on what Gregory was talking about. Um
when we're all talking about the uh
dosage and we are talking about the
grams and how we're going to administer
the dosage to people, uh I guess uh what
my input would be would be the testing.
uh we have to start somewhere and
testing is where we come to a to a
agreed upon like um like he was saying
the variation between different fruit
bodies and the content of psilocybin in
those fruit bodies. So telling people to
take a gram of this or a gram of that um
it doesn't really work. Uh what would be
a better method would be to test the uh
the fruit bodies and uh determine what
the percentage or content of the act
psychoactive ingredient or what we're
actually here for which would be
psilocybin um the medical program of
psil psilocybin. So uh once that's uh
determined then uh there is a formula to
um I guess to con uh to calculate what
the conversion of the uh actual active
compound in the body which would be
solosin. So um the standard that we have
on that should be should be set
according to uh something that we can
apply across the board. Um that's what
my that was my only input that I really
wanted to give and so um the the
conversion I did put into the chat
people can look it over and that we have
to be able to agree on on uh absolutes.
So whether or not a person can handle
that much of a uh dosage or not will
have to be determined by a physician and
the person the individual themselves.
Also uh some of these other tryptoamine
compounds that are in fruit bodies um
also play a role in the effect or the uh
experience and so but the superseding uh
psychoactive compound is psilocybin and
so uh and then um well is solosin.
[snorts]
So um those things all need to be taken
into consideration when setting dosage
guidelines and not fruit body weight or
uh because for the general consensus
some people will say 100 milligrams of
fruit bodies is a micro dose but what is
the percentage of solosin in that 100
milligrams or gram uh and there are
conversion rates for that and you can
determine all those things through a lab
uh through lab testing. So once we have
that and we have the lab testing uh and
we all have a set uh you know formula
that um things can be measured by uh
then we can start talking about what is
the dosage that's adequate for an
individual and what isn't and until we
get there then we can't really we can't
really do that. So uh that's my input
and thank you guys for listening.
>> Thank you.
>> Aaliyah your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hi. Um, [clears throat]
with micro doing
you do not feel high from it if it's a
true micro dose.
You don't have hallucinations. You're
fully functional to be able to do
whatever you're normally doing in your
life. Um, it's not true that you don't
feel anything. You can feel uplifted.
You can feel your nervous system be
calmer, your mind be calmer and clearer.
You can have enhanced awareness of
things. Um, yet you're fully functional.
In fact, it's in according to the
research, you're even can be a lot more
functional in anything that you're doing
in your life and have more vitality,
more creative energy uh for anything
that you're doing in your life. It's not
it's
I think it would be ridiculous to
require people to go into a clinic to
receive a micro dose if it's a true
micro dose and it would be more
expensive for those for anybody that is
wanting to do micro doing. You can have
tre tremendous results for micro doing
for all kinds of things in your life.
According to the lots and lots of
research, it can help to create new
neural pathways in your brain. It can
help to heal your nervous system and it
can enhance your memory. It can uplift
your energy
um and mood. Um it can help to clear
inflammation.
Um it can help to enhance your
consciousness of a a higher level of
consciousness. And there's absolutely no
reason for people to have to go into a
clinic to get that to get a micro dose.
And it would just be I mean then you'd
have to pay a clinic to get a micro dose
uh you know to for some somebody to
serve you with a micro dose. And there's
no reason to have to have a chauffeur to
take you home. I mean it's it's
ridiculous. You don't have to do that
with marijuana. Why would you have to do
that with a micro dose where you're
feeling even less than you do with
marijuana?
I think that's a ridiculous law. Um it's
just it's very um limiting. It's it
would be very limiting for the benefits
of for a vast number of people in New
Mexico. And it's really upsetting to me
that to hear that that's the law and
that really needs to be changed ASAP.
I do just want to add um it's also like
not my opinion that they should have to
go to outpatient. That was just my
solution that would be compliant with
the law. I'm just trying to follow the
what they've given us to do. The
legislature has been incredibly kind in
delegating legislative authority to this
board. Um, so I don't want to be
disrespectful and say, "Hey, we're just
going to completely ignore what you guys
wrote." Um, and also unlawful, but um, I
I I want to make the record clear. I do
stand behind being able to have a micro
dose at home. Um, I I just agree with
that point. However, under the current
law, that that's where the complications
like come in. I just wanted to like it
to be understood that I'm not just like
if that wasn't in the law I wouldn't
just be like will they still have to go
to an outpatient. I'm just trying to
come up with solutions that are within
SB219.
>> And good morning everybody. Uh this is
Dominic again and I just want to be
clear the bill itself does not exclude
micro dosing. Some of the comments kind
of being made I think were getting down
the wrong path and in the wrong way. It
also does not exclude individuals using
at home. What it does exclude is that it
excludes people using it outside of a
therapeutic or medicinal uh setting and
that's the approved setting. And so one
of the things that we have been looking
at as far as for example with hospice
and I've actually been on the record in
fact I discussed this in a podcast just
yesterday um that some of the things
we're looking at is how do we do that?
We cannot expect a patient who is not
ambulatory, who is not able to move and
is has to stay in their bed. Um, we can
expect them to move not only to, you
know, 10 or 20 or 100 miles down the
road to go to a clinic, but you know, or
just even down the hallway. Sometimes we
have to figure out ways of doing that.
That can be done as facilitation.
So some of the things we've talked about
is will there be ways for the
facilitators to visit in the home to be
able to do dosing. We understand that
creates an issue when people are talking
about micro dose. I will be very clear
during and people can go back and look
at what was occurring at the roundhouse
in the last session. They have all of
the videos of the committee meetings and
everything else in there. The way that
the bill was presented was doing this in
clinical settings, therapeutic settings
um and doing this with the model of the
integrative therapy before the journey
and then integrative therapy afterwards.
So it did not come in with regard to
that. We are trying to figure out and
that's what this committee in part is
about is how do we take some of these
opportunities for figuring [snorts] out
how do we serve those individuals to be
able who cannot leave home? How do we
serve them in a way that's going to work
within the framework of the statute? The
statute does say it has to be an
approved setting. There are different
ways we could potentially define that
which could include making sure that
there is that trained certified
individual there to assist with the
dosing, make sure the protocol is
followed. Um, this is not a
decriminalization bill and we need to
make sure that people are understanding
it is not a decriminalization bill. It
is a bill for medical use only. That
means it has to be done in a therapeutic
session. Can that therapeutic session
potentially be in someone's home? Yes.
But what are those conditions going to
be? That is a part of what this group is
about of how do we set up those
requirements, those protocols in order
to do it within the statute. And my
concern is just everyone, we're seeing a
lot of comments in here about we have to
do this, we have to do this. We there
are things that we're going to try to do
as best we can to serve as many patients
as possible, but it has to be done
within the statute. And I'm also going
to uh recommend um because we do have a
time limit with a hard stop at 11:00 um
and there are a lot of people I know who
want to speak on this. I'm going to
recommend that we do set a time limit.
Ian, what do you think would be u
appropriate? uh and this is just of
course as people talk if after
afterwards there we have additional time
people can also speak again at that
point but uh there are a lot of people
who want to get their their thoughts out
and we want to make sure this is a place
for that but I would recommend say a
three minute limit which is what we
usually do during public comments during
the meeting I see Ian is nodding his
head um and again we'll go through the
list and then once we reach to the end
if people would like to speak again we
can call on people again um so that we
can go ahead and do that. Okay. Um so
thank you everybody and with that I'll
turn it back over to Jorge for the next
individual. Um and again just because
there's amount of time we want to make
sure the people who have who have their
hands up to speak. So, please go ahead
read through what is in the comments.
Um, that we'll make sure that's included
in uh as far as when once the meeting is
over, people can still access them for a
little while. Uh, so that if people have
ideas and items like that. So, um, uh,
anyway, in that case, Jorge, if you'll
go on to the next person.
Brett, your mic has been enabled. please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> All right, thank you guys. Yeah, having
some good discussion here. Um, yeah, I
think one, you know, one element of
this, uh, I think I I think Dominic
nailed a lot of what I was going to say
about the approved setting is really all
that's all that's in the the law, you
know, and what that means is going to be
up to the up to the the board and and
the department. And you know, I think
it's okay for uh you know, Ian, if if
you feel strongly about something, I
think there's room for interpretation on
those kind of things that you don't have
to you know, you don't have to
necessarily withhold your own beliefs as
the as the chairman of the of the board,
you know, and ultimately if DO doesn't
like it, then they don't have to accept
that either, you know. Um and if the
legislature doesn't like what DO comes
up with, then they don't, you know, they
they can always modify the law. But I
think you're on the right track of how
do we make this as expansive as
possible. And one angle on this that we
talked a lot about in another committee
um is the use of tele medicine um and
how that may be able to help facilitate
some of these issues that that people
are bringing up um in the context of
people being able to you know use the
medicine at at home. Um I think allowing
particularly in the end of life care or
hospice for for things to be done um at
home as as an approved setting you know
that's a that's a very broad definition
that we're going to have to define and I
think the the access we have to tele
medicine the state has has done a lot
with that in the last several years
since co and and really understands how
to use that. So, I just would would
recommend that. Um, and I think given
given practitioners a lot of discretion
in terms of dosage and and those type of
things, you know, that's the kind of
thing that um is probably best handled
between a a doctor and patient or
provider and and patient. Um, so I would
just advise to not be too strict in
terms of what the what the dosage
requirements through the um through the
regulations look like. But yeah, thanks
again. and I appreciate all the
conversation on this and Dominic, thanks
for keeping us heading in the right
direction.
>> Thank you.
>> Cameron, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself.
Excuse [clears throat] me. Please unmute
yourself to speak.
>> All right. Hi everybody again. Um, I
can't agree more with uh Greg Evans that
we really need to move away from this
language of micro do, macro dose, heroic
dose. Those are all based on individual
subjective measurements.
Um, the word that we're really looking
for is titration, which means anything
just above zero all the way up to, you
know, grams of active compound or um it
or
um metabolize
um psilocybin. So the with titration
that I think what would be most
beneficial is um before we try to intend
giving anyone like a real active dose um
I think we should work them up from zero
titrate them up um to where we find that
activity line for each individual
patient.
Um once we do that then the true like
active dose can be determined for that
specific patient.
I also think that there might be room
for
um extraction.
If there is a mushroom extraction then
we can actually dose out um silosin or
psilocybin whichever we can extract out
and that person's dosage can be
essentially measured for each person.
And um that way even if you grind up the
mushroom um there could still
potentially be hot spots um depending on
the
size of the grind. Um I think in several
uh patents that I've read through about
extraction
the the the particle size was like 40
micron. Um, so we're going to have to
like require some um specific equipment
for uh the the grinding just to avoid
hot spots because in the cap you have a
higher density of silosin and psilocybin
versus the stem. Um, also the other
alkyoids that produce the entourage
effect, those are uh in in different
amounts in the cap versus the the stem.
Um I would also like to say that you
know to everyone that is talking about
micro doing and um even the the larger
dose uh effects
um all of the the the micro doing
research um all of that data was
supplied by
uh people themselves. It was not
recorded in a laboratory setting.
that data was was self-reported data.
So,
um there's a lot of subjective
discrepancies within micro doing
research. That's not to say that
the the effects of u
uh nartogenesis
um don't exist. Um a lot of
>> you have 30 seconds.
>> Okay. Yeah. I I I do believe that
neurogenesis is a part of it, but a lot
of that research is um in vitro and
animal model research and the in vitro
is with human recep 5HT 2-way receptors.
So we still have yet to see the effect
of
um the neurogenesis that is present with
all the psychedelics but it is there.
>> Thank you Cameron.
James Brown, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
Thank you, sir. Hey, a couple of topics
here that we haven't talked about yet.
Um [clears throat] would be the
inclusion criteria or exclusion criteria
that Ian brought up earlier. I think
that's going to be important to look at
as a group. Um, a lot of literature out
there, but what really uh, you know, a
lot of stuff with the SSRIs, the MOAS,
um, that stuff right now is being looked
at as, you know, do they really need to
taper down or can you dose those and
keep the patient on those if they're on
that polyfarm pharmacy style. Uh,
something to look at and talk about um,
with our group. Also, something to look
at is those um,
informed consents. I think it's going to
be important that you know we look at
this the different settings um and then
what consent does it a one for all or is
there different consents for the
different settings um I like to talk
about access as well um as we push these
models one of the big things in Oregon
is sometimes the patients have to show
up and get their dose at the center and
it's very hard for those patients to
access the centers and get there all the
So something to look at is our therapy
plans. And I really think that we need
to be specific in our therapy plans for
our different settings and really look
at what um that entails. You know, what
does the literature say, but also what
can we do to allow access here in New
Mexico with our therapy plans. Um and
that'll include the dosing and and where
it can happen and all that stuff. Um but
definitely we need to look at things
like what's happening with the cannabis.
Um as the centers open up and there's so
many centers in the various communities
in New Mexico are going to be very
different. Um rural versus industrial
you know if we go to Albuquerque the
centers are going to be maybe abundant.
If we go rural you know Clovis
Farmington Los Cusus how many centers
really going to happen and how much
access can happen there. So something to
think about. Um and also
>> James, you have one minute.
>> You have one minute, James.
>> Um and and capturing this data is will
be important for this group to think
about and everything that we do with
this data and how do we keep the process
going. Um and I like to talk about that
with with you guys too is with um that
periodic review. Um what how often do we
want to review everything? Literature is
coming out all the time. Um, and how
viable is that literature? Is there that
bias in there? Is that written by
somebody's being sponsored by somebody
else? So, really look at that. And how
often do we look at that? Periodic
review will be important as well as um
just getting together. I'm so excited.
Again, thank you
um Ian and Dominic. Thank you Ian for
heading this up. I really appreciate
you. And that'll be it. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Cameron, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Yeah, I just wanted to touch on some
concerns about being able to uh
prescribe and the stuff to where people
could take it home. I know that there
was a big concern in the medical
cannabis program that people outside of
the the the people that were prescribed
were getting a hold of the medication.
Um so if people are supervised when
they're taking the medication
um you could eliminate this potential
problem of spread um that is beyond um
the who is intended to take the
medication. Um, I would also like to say
that um
the the approved settings um probably
need to be taken into account with uh a
medical
um perspective
in that if we don't know how somebody
responds to this stuff, I think maybe
for the first
couple of sessions that that should be
done maybe within city limits to where
if somebody does have a problem that the
paramedics could reach you and treat
this particular person until we know how
they respond to the medication. Um, I
think that can't be overstated as I've
seen um, bzzoazipines
uh, have been
pretty important for people that are
um, experiencing adverse effects or
agitated states that they you can't
reason them out of. Um and obviously we
we wouldn't be able to give them
benzoazipines but um in the ED the
emergency room um that is part of their
protocol is administering benzoazipines.
Um so
I think uh we really need to consider
the
>> Cameron Cameron you have one minute.
>> Okay.
Um but yeah, that that was my point. My
whole point was um knowing how your
um who you're treating is going to
respond.
Thank you,
>> Patricia. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you. Uh my name is Patricia
Stellar. Sorry, I missed the
introductions. Um, but I wanted to just
kind of add to a couple of other
comments that were made um specific to
the dosage considerations. Um, like to
be the most efficacious, I don't think
that this can or should be mandated by
the government in this program. I think
like someone else had mentioned really
having that be a decision between the
provider and the patient in a way just
having some agency. We can have
guidelines, but I think being overly
prescriptive about you start here, you
go here, you go here, like it's it's not
quite like that. Um, in my experience,
and another thing I wanted to mention is
that multiple people mentioned BMI. And
I'm not a doctor or scientist, but in my
experience working with this medicine
with myself and others, um, BMI has not
correlated with impacts of dosage. I've
seen large men and small women taking
the same batch, same setting, same
preparation, same experience like um
with the same dose very differently. And
so I think a lot of that is like close
observation um also like Gregory and
someone else had mentioned really
starting from the point of zero and
working up you know very closely with
that person and whatever that setting
looks like. I think it would be very
cost prohibitive to only make that step
up process be in medical settings. Um,
but that's just my opinion from my
experience. I think the home setting is
super important not only for micro doing
but as an available option for those
that um are not uh are not in favor of
western medicine and have not, you know,
or that has failed them and they're
seeking this. Obviously, there's also a
ton of people that only want to have
this, you know, administered by doctors
and and medical providers, too. Um, so
just kind of adding to that that echo of
considering the home as a clinical
setting and then defining how that can
be done um in the ways that, you know,
we feel comfortable with as a community
in ways that also incorporate uh the
grandma in the rural place or people
that have mobility issues.
>> Patricia, you have one minute remaining.
>> Thank you. Um, I also want to agree with
a comment that I had made regarding just
the the protocols being over overly
cumbersome in cost and limiting access.
Um, just speaking with some some places
that have called in Colorado. Um,
I've just found it a little bit obscene
some of the requirements there that that
are reasons why it makes it incredibly
costly. Um, so I think just
it's important to have parameters and
guidelines, but also having those be
adaptable um, depending on, you know,
the circumstance and and taking into
account safety. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Ian, did you want to you have your hand
raised? Let's You are the chair. So,
>> yeah, I just wanted to um add on to
that. um she had mentioned that dosage
should not be prescriptive and I
couldn't agree more what I had um
originally
kind of been thinking about not official
or anything just how I had envisioned
it. So we would have a
micro dose tier um that would be
like I don't know I'll throw out a
number less than a gram assuming that it
was impacted by BMI. Um, and then we'll
have another tier that'll go low
therapeutic that'll be um like one to
three. Then medium therapeutic would be
three to six. And then six and above
would be high. I don't think we should
tell them you should prescribe this
dose. I think we should give them a
range, but then we can add specific
safety mechanisms like additional
screening um for particular dosage
categories. That way we're not being
overly burdensome for like a micro dose
while still working within the confines
of the law.
>> Thank you, Ian. Uh Ian, also just want
to inform you that there are a lot of
comments in the chat. Uh I'm not going
to read them all for sake of time, but
we will download those and include those
in the minutes and we'll continue on
with the speakers.
Dan, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hello again everybody. Dan from Oregon
laboratory here in Oregon. Um I really
feel like um people go in at least here
in Oregon and Colorado for certain
uh they're they're seeking certain
relief and um the relief
requires different dosages for different
types of relief. So starting people at
the bare minimum and working them up um
I don't feel that's beneficial. Um I
also feel like if you guys are going to
do a medical uh model um and I heard the
speaker earlier about the cannabis how
medical everybody was worried about it
getting into the uh hands of people that
are not uh do not have a prescription.
Um, but I hate to say it, but I I have a
feeling that um, opioids and
prescription drugs end up in the hands
of people that do not have a
prescription. So, um, I would, you know,
I I really believe that micro doses 1 to
2 milligrams total equivalents
psilocybin
um, should be able to be sent home with
the people. you know that you can put
things in place where they can sign
paperwork and do all whatever they need
to do and be informed that you know you
cannot share and if you are caught
sharing or whatever then you could be
held liable. Um
that's basically it. I just I really
feel like micro dosis is um
subperceptual dose and um I I I I'm I do
lean towards if somebody is new to this
um maybe have one or two micro dose
sessions in inhouse um just to make
everybody feel at ease um but then at
that point no side effects send them
home with some micro doses um I do not
recommend sending people home with
anything more than a micro dose
Um, set and setting and purpose is all
part of it. Sorry. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Denali, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
Good morning, everyone. Um, thank you,
Chair Dunn, for facilitating this
important conversation.
Um, I jumped in a little bit late and so
I'm sorry if if others have have
mentioned this consideration when it
comes to approved settings, but I uh I I
wanted to zoom out a little bit and talk
about the the room for flexibility that
exists in in New Mexico just given the
model that we've that we've adopted. Um,
both Oregon and Colorado are service
center models. that means that the the
agency is licensing a brickandmortar
space. Um that's not the model that New
Mexico adopted, right? Our authorization
is to providers and healthcare entities,
which then I I think, you know, we'd
really be missing an opportunity um if
we don't take advantage of the
flexibility that allows. and and it it's
really a demonstration of our values of
trusting
supervising care providers to make the
the best decisions for the people in
their care. Um I I want to mention, you
know, I I echo everything that's been
said about inhome accessibility.
Another option again that is available
to us outside of a service center model
like Oregon and Colorado is considering
um outdoor settings. And I think, you
know, in a state like New Mexico where
we are just um blessed to be in such a
beautiful um a beautiful state with so
many beautiful
um and and amazing places to explore in
the natural world. I mean, anyone who
anyone who's had had an experience in in
nature um knows that, you know, some of
the deepest healing is really possible.
Um, and I think that there are ways for
us to uh create the kind of safety that
that we need to within within a retreat
style or temporary approval for for a na
a nature-based um healing experience.
Um,
>> and you have one minute.
>> Another another speaker mentioned, you
know, maybe limiting things to to city
limits. Um, I think we can be a little
bit more expansive to that and still get
to what that speaker was saying about,
you know, accessibility and and
closeness of EMS and and other safety
considerations. You know, how much
control can we make sure that people
have over the environment and uh, you
know, public access, these kinds of
things. So, um, eager to be in continued
conversation about the the
wide variety of opportunities that are
available to us here.
>> Thank you,
>> James Brown. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you again, everyone. And just
probably last comments of the day. Um,
I'd like to talk a little bit about that
teleaalth option. I really think that we
need to be utilizing that. I think that
was a great point earlier and it's also
been discussed prior. I think our
virtual access is going to be important
and allowing that virtual access with
those consents. Um, it'll be very
important for us to do um because this
again is rural and you know we don't
want to fail with this. If we want to be
very successful with our access to our
people, we we deserve that and we need
that here in New Mexico. We don't we're
very limited in providers and as we
teach and train these people to become
facilitators.
They need to be aware of what you know
what's out there for them. And access is
going to be a big again I can't end
enough with that. Um but I think again
we look at teleaalth as well as my last
piece instead of administration
sessions. Um it hasn't been talked about
very much yet and I want to bring that
up to everybody. Um my best experiences
and what I've been learning is that
hands-off method. You know individual
containers are very important for
individuals to heal and self-grow. And
so with those containers, I think with
the administration sessions when we look
at hands-off type of techniques to help
them. Um, and so that'll be a great
discussion points is what [snorts] do we
do during the administration sessions
and what is allowed and what's not
allowed and what consents need to be
done prior to that during that
preparation phase. You know, getting
that person or individual ready for
their experience and their growth and
their healing. It's going to require a
lot of time and effort, but also it's
going to see during that administration,
you know, what's allowed during it. Um,
there's a lot of new techniques and a
lot of research out there about
>> James, you have one minute.
>> Different things or activities during
the administration session. I think
that's a sticky point. Um, so we need to
really open that up. I think we need to
be very broad and vague to when somebody
is doing their administration session
that they're allowed to have different
experiences and not limit them. So look,
let's look at that. So thank you again
everybody.
Thank you.
>> James Hov, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Excellent. Thank you. Can you guys hear
me? Okay. Yes, we can.
>> Okay. Thank you. Um, I'd just like to
touch on something I don't think um, has
been spoken about yet, but after a
personal uh, GI visit for a procedure, I
think we should really model the
postsocybin decision-m safeguards in
relative to really informing and
educating the patients to be explicit to
not make any major decisions or sign
important documents for a defined period
post uh, procedure or excuse me this
medical psilocybin session. I deeply
believe that altered states from
psilocybin even when therapeutic can
impair judgment, suggestability um and
even emotional regulation. So similar I
think with the post session protections
should be built into the clinical
practice guidelines. I really appreciate
all the comments and I'm really excited
how this all progresses. Thank you for
hearing me out.
Thank you.
And Ian, those are all the hands.
>> All righty, guys. So, thank you so much
for sharing. Um, one thing I kind of
heard um multiple times was that the
dosage um
Oh my god, my brain just blinked.
Anyway, um that the dose that the
administration could be done by having
um the facilitator go to their home. I
think if we defined an approved setting
as with a facilitator that would pass
the litmus test of okay, is this medical
and therapeutic and with a um
facilitator as the current law requires?
um cuz the approved setting isn't the
only part of the bill that kind of uh
makes at home a little bit more
difficult. So, for instance, the bill
requires that we have an administration
and um I mean a preparation and
administration and an integration
session, which if you're having them do
multiple doses throughout the week, that
could become a little bit more um
difficult. Working within the confines
of the law though, I think if we had a
facilitator be able to go to people's
houses, that would a solve our hospice
problem. It would be allow people who
are maybe um unable to leave their home
for whatever reason to still have access
to treatment um and would actually be a
legally defensible approved setting
versus a just a home in and of itself.
Um,
I have been working with the legislature
to try to um, a couple of different
representatives to try and see if we can
get micro doing. I am going to let you
guys know they are very concerned that
this program is going to turn into
recreational use. So, that's kind of
what they've been um, letting me know.
And so
that micro dose might be a little bit
harder until we have cuz I want you guys
to remember that this was the first law
that was passed for New Mexico on
psilocybin.
Um like the medical cannabis program uh
it had an original law and then was
greatly expanded in 2019. So just like
that, we may need to practice some of
the, you know, more burdensome options
like having a facilitator go to your
house. But if that turns out to be
successful, um
um
once the the micro dose in an outpatient
clinic is successful, then we are able
to say, okay, maybe we can just have it
at home. But right now there's so little
data on widespread access and allowing
access to psilocybin that we don't want
to create a bunch of problems allowing
people to take it home and then all of
the sudden there's
a problem in the program or something
happens or you know life comes at you
and I just want to make sure that we are
protected on all sides because I believe
this is just the start of the program.
This is the the in my view this is the
most
restrictive the program will be. It will
open with time. Um but we have to let
the legislature see how this program is
working where the flaws are. We may be
able to identify them now. They like a
little bit more hard evidence. Um so I
just want you all to keep your minds
open. Um, this isn't the final I mean it
is the law, but this is not I have
serious doubts that this will be the
final law on the issue.
>> You know, we do have one hand raised.
[clears throat] So, whenever you're
ready, just let me know.
>> Go for it.
>> Okay,
>> Jesse, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Good morning. Um just to touch on this
uh the therapy uh there's a company
called Psych Psychedelic Passage out of
Colorado and the way they do it is a
fivew week session two weeks with a
therapist. they'll first analyze
uh your intention and what you're trying
to help yourself with and then there's a
week of ceremony
um and then two a twoe integration after
that and I think that's kind of a great
model to maybe adopt or at least look
into um I was talking to them years ago
about doing a journey with them and they
told me that they were actually
interested in uh branching off into New
Mexico. So, that might be something that
we want to, you know, work with and and
uh hopefully get some resources from
them.
That's it. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> All righty. And now that our time is
almost up, we have about 15 minutes
left. I'm going to go ahead and
summarize the orders of the day. We
passed our bylaws and had some great
discussion about micro doing about um
facilitation approved settings. It has
been a very productive conversation. I
expect us to meet every 2 weeks.
However, um one thing I was looking into
if you guys are interested is having a
joint committee meeting with the patient
qualification and safety committee. That
would allow us to do all of the like
preparation stuff. So if they have to do
any preparation documents, we can look
at the patient qualification and safety
committee's exclusion criteria and then
we can look at our dosage criteria and
we can kind of blend them to make uh uh
like the preparation session
requirements. Um so that's what I have
planned. So let me see what dates um
work for y'all. I know I'm usually
pretty good on um Friday mornings,
otherwise the afternoon is probably the
best for me, but I will let you guys um
decide
I um just looking and with some of the
items here um I would recommend Friday
the 30th at this point in time does not
have other meetings scheduled at this
point.
>> And that would be that would be
basically two weeks and then moving it
to Friday rather than Wednesday.
>> Friday the Okay, cool.
>> So
>> all right. I would recommend say from 1
to 3 on Friday the 30th.
>> I would be okay with that if you guys
want to throw up a quick thumbs up if
you guys are good or yes in chat works.
Cool.
>> Okay, I'm seeing the majority of yes.
And just as a reminder, uh you know,
we're never going to be able to have
schedules for everybody. that's going to
work for every single person that is
here. Um, and uh, just to answer the
another question in there about the
subsequent meetings, what we are doing
is we are posting that on the medical
psilocybin page in the announcements
section. And so we're posting those. We
are batching them. Um, and so you'll
actually see the notice for the next
round of meetings coming out. [snorts]
Uh, we were actually waiting for this
meeting to finish. So, it'll be coming
out either later today or tomorrow on
that announcement page. Um, and then we
also do send them out through the uh the
update email list, which if you're
interested in signing up for it, uh just
so everybody knows, you go to the
www.nmhealth.org
page and in the upper right hand area,
you click on the sign up for e-news.
Once you click on there, you just
complete your basic information. Um and
then you can select the medical
psilocybin program checkbox. You can
also check any other uh topics that you
may be interested in to get those
updates from the department. And then
just make sure you click sign up the big
yellowish orange box at the bottom. Um
and uh sometimes depending on your own
system, you may have to confirm you are
not a robot. And then we will also be
sending it out through there again like
I said in the next couple of days. But
then we do have that and we'll be
sending that out. Part of the [snorts]
reason we're doing that is because many
people are involved in multiple
committees and so we're going to be
batching them uh every week or so simply
so that we do not overwhelm email boxes
with lots of uh emails um because
especially for some of the board members
who are involved in all of the
committees. There are seven committees
plus the board itself um plus other
announcements that we do send out
through there occasionally um to update
people. So we don't want to uh just
overburden people. So this right now at
this point is our best method. Um so
that's what we're essentially doing. And
then the other aspect just in case
anybody has additional information or
wants to check in what the links are for
the website is medical.silocybin
dooh.n.gov
and the program website which is where
the announcements are. It's on that
first page and then you just scroll down
a little bit and it shows the
announcements. Uh, in fact, I'll go
ahead and let me share just so everyone
can actually see it. Um,
pardon me for just a moment while I
switch to actually showing that screen.
So, for example, this one shows the
current list and the current, for
example, all the committee dates and
times. This is for the ones that are
going on right now. Um, and so there
will be a new announcement here in the
next day or two that will show the next
round of uh announcements. And just in
case, so everybody has it in the chat, I
am putting the that particular page in
the chat directly.
So, there is a link to that page. Um,
okay. And I think that's all I have. Oh,
the other item just to let everybody
know is while we do po post the
recordings onto the psilocybin advisory
board and then they go on to the meeting
records page. So just to give an example
um and then the meetings that happened
last year which were in December and uh
they did post the first one on January
16th for the next the upcoming board
meeting on this Friday. Um but then 26
they're already starting to post
[snorts] some of those documents and the
recordings. Um it does take between our
uh the review that it has to go through
internally in case there's anything such
as inappropriate uh language or anything
else. Um and then what we do is that
gets posted. It does take between 5 to
10 business days. So please be patient.
It is a large volume of items being
generated by all of these different
committees, but we are adding all of
those items in. So, uh, thank you very
much everyone and I'll go back to you
Ian. Ian, there's one hand raised.
>> Sure. Uh, Lady Deos.
>> Larry, your your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Hi. Can you guys hear me?
>> Yes, we can. Okay, I just want to say
thank you so much for this. It's been so
educational, so helpful. Just knowing
that this exists,
I don't know, put delight in my head and
just the potential to help as many
people as possible to show them that
this is more than just this is for
medicinal purposes. And yes, if it goes
recreational, then fine may be, but
alternatively, this is a medicine that
can help people, enhance their lives.
So, thank you all for everything, all
the comments. Um, yeah, I hope you guys
have a blessed day.
>> Thank you.
>> That's all, Lean.
>> All [clears throat] righty. Well, I
guess I will call this meeting
adjourned. I am so happy that all of you
were able to join. I wish you guys a
great rest of your January, and I will
see you at the end.
>> Thank you everybody.